One day, you will sip from the Fountain of Memory.
总有一天 你将饮下记忆之泉的水
When that day comes, we will meet again.
到那一天 我们还会再见
Time again, you prove to be no more than dead weight.
再一次证明了你就是一堆没脑子的傻肉
Perhaps you should mark me a traitor,
也许你应该把我
and have me killed as well.
也当成叛徒宰了
People underestimate you, Giuliano,
人们会低估你 朱利亚诺
Yet that perceived weakness makes you suited,
而这种观念使你特别适合
to flushing out a spy from cover.
从暗处抓出间谍
You're the one that slipped those documents into my quarters.
是你把那些文件放进了我的房间
How long have they owned you?
你变节多久了?
You are just as exasperating as she was!
你跟她一样惹人生气!
- Is she dead?  - No difference, she's gone.
- 她死了吗?  - 没什么区别 她离开了
That's why you can't stand to look at me because she left you.
所以你才不敢直视我 因为她离开你了
- I saw a man.  - Who was it, Leonardo?
- 我看到一个人  - 他是谁 莱昂纳多?
Free me.
放开我
- What did you see?  - It was me.
- 你看到了什么?  - 是我自己
Is this madness?
这是疯了吗?
How... how could it be?
怎么... 怎么可能?
In that cave...
在那个洞里...
Free me.
放开我
How could I have seen myself...
我还是个孩子...
when I was not yet myself?
怎么可能看到成年的自己?
The sons of Mithras have been entwined with your destiny,
在你出生的很久之前 密特拉之子
since long before you were born, Leonardo.
就与你的宿命纠缠在了一起 莱昂纳多
Time is a river,
时间是一条河流
and there are members of our fraternity who have learned,
而我们中有些成员已经学会了
to navigate it both upstream and downstream.
顺流而下和逆流而上
You may think that you're not yet yourself.
你可能会觉得自己还不是自己
But, in every moment, you are both the child you once were,
不过在每一刻 你都既是那个曾经的顽童
and the sage you will some day be.
又是将会成为的圣贤
- That's not an answer.  - I never promised you answers.
- 这不是答案  - 我从没答应过给你答案
For those, you will need to find the book of leaves.
找答案的话 你要找到叶之书
Answers to questions that haunt all men.
牵绊着全人类问题的答案
Questions that haunt you.
也有你心中问题的答案
- The fate of my mother.  - And more.
- 我母亲的命运  - 还有更多
I speak of your destiny.
我说的是你的命运
Much as I enjoy the entertainment, signor,
我很欣赏这表演 阁下
we came to talk to the duke about hiring his mercenaries,
我们是来跟公爵讨论雇佣他的佣兵的
not to watch them beat each other senseless.
不是来看他们毫无意义的斗殴
Some mead, fine sirs?
先生们 来点蜂蜜酒吗?
Thank you. Yes, indeed.
谢谢 对 好的
We mull it with a little honey.
我们加了点蜂蜜
The pride of the duchy of Urbino.
乌尔比诺公爵领地的特产
- A little honey?  - Just fucking drink it.
- 一点蜂蜜?  - 别废话 快喝
Brilliant! Bravo!
漂亮! 厉害!
- Medici!  - Urbino!
- 美第奇!  - 乌尔比诺!
You know you fight like a man who's not seen battle for far too long.
你战斗的样子像是一个渴望战斗很久的人
It's been too many years. Yes.
是啊 已经都很多年了
Federico Da Montefeltro, Duke of Urbino.
我是费德里科・达・蒙泰费尔特罗 乌尔比诺公爵
Leonardo Da Vinci.
这位是莱昂纳多・达芬奇
Reading? My!
居然在看书? 天啊!
This primer was given to me by Gentile Becchi.
这本启蒙读物是金泰尔・贝奇给我的
You mourn him still.
你还在怀念他
How may I serve you, sister-in-law?
嫂子 我有什么可以为你效劳的?
We are due to hold a pageant for Martedi Grasso, some days hence.
过些日子 我们要给马尔泰迪・格拉索举行一场宴会
I hoped you might escort me.
希望你可以陪我
Even if Lorenzo returns from his diplomatic forays,
就算洛伦佐从外交活动上回来了
he usually finds pressing business when the revels begin.
宴会一开始他总是要找些公事去做
At least he pays for the revels.
至少他付了宴会的钱
But what is a lady to do for a partner?
可是我去又有什么用呢?
I can only thank heaven Lorenzo has a brother,
我只能感谢洛伦佐还有个弟弟
who knows his way around a dance floor.
而且舞技了得
Mm. You must forgive me, but I have a plot to unravel.
嗯 请原谅 我还有计划要布置
Becchi charged me with ferreting out the spy within our midst.
贝奇让我负责查出我们之中的内鬼
But the evidence against Becchi was overwhelming.
可是证明贝奇是内鬼的证据确凿
Testament to the ability of our spy.
事实证明了内鬼的能力
He is a kind of genius.
他是个天才
I will soldier on at the revels without you, then.
那么宴会的时候 我只能一个人了
I'm touched at your dedication.
我已经被你的奉献精神打动了
The fact that, for all your opportunities...
事实上 你机遇无限...
you're so intent on doing the right thing.
而却只想做正确的事
Maybe your most attractive quality.
也许这就是你最有魅力的品质
My lady, it is time.
夫人 该服药了
My personal torturer has arrived.
我的私刑又到了
- You know we have no choice.  - Mm.
- 你知道我们没得选择  - 嗯
Twice a day, I must down this potion,
经过早些年的失败 如果我想生个儿子
if I'm to produce a boy, after my earlier failures.
就要每天两次 喝这个方子
Oh, Moses, tell Giuliano what's in this.
摩西 告诉朱利亚诺这里都有什么
I cannot bring myself to say the words.
我自己说不出口
Asses' milk, powdered goats' antlers,
驴奶 鹿茸粉
Bull's testicles...
公牛睾丸....
Giuliano, you could spare me this liquid atrocity,
朱利亚诺 你要是能生个儿子
if you would father a son yourself.
我就不用喝这个了
If we do not produce a male heir soon,
如果我们再不赶紧生个儿子
somewhere in our line,
或者没有直系的子嗣降生
the house of Medici will start,
美第奇家族将会
to look like an unstable investment.
变成不稳定的投资项目
We each have our duty, I see.
我们都有自己的职责 我明白
Salut.
干杯
It's there.
在那里
Logic dictates that land lies due west.
从位置上看这块大陆在西方
You think the identification of a simple cardinal direction,
你觉得只是需要辨别出一个简单的基本方向
is all you need to find your goal?
就可以达到目的?
It's all I need to get started.
足够让我开始行动了
You could spend a hundred lifetimes traveling west,
你可能得花上百辈子的时间一直向西
could you not?
明白吗?
The map Avraham Ben Yosef brought to Florence,
阿乌拉罕・本・尤瑟夫带到佛罗伦萨来的地图
is not an original, but a reproduction,
不是原始的 只是一张副本
riddled with notations that only one man can decipher.
布满其中的标记只有一个人能够解读
The cartographer who copied it.
就是复制它的绘图者
- Another son of mithras?  - His name is Solomon Ogbai.
- 又是个密特拉之子?  - 他的名字叫所罗门・奥拜
We call him the abyssinian.
我们叫他阿比西尼亚人
Lucky for you, he is not dead.
对你来说幸运的是 他还没死
Not yet.
暂时还没有
You have yet to save him.
你还可以救他
His retinue was brutally intercepted,
他在为土耳其苏丹效力的时候
while he was traveling under the employ of the Ottoman Sultan.
被粗暴地劫持了
A most savage warlord holds him captive.
一个野蛮的军阀拿他当做战俘
The abyssinian cannot be freed by simple diplomacy, or even ransom.
外交手段甚至赎金 都换不回他
It will take guile and inventiveness which only you possess.
只能依靠你的奸诈和创造性了
These are delicate times. I have commitments to Florence.
很微妙的时刻 我跟佛罗伦萨有委任关系
Your destiny lies elsewhere, Leonardo.
你的宿命不在佛罗伦萨 莱昂纳多
Save the abyssinian while he still breathes.
趁阿比西亚人还活着把他救出来
I have to think it over, I can't...
我必须再考虑考虑 不能...
You've already thought it over.
你已经考虑好了
In truth, your journey has already begun.
事实上 你的旅途已经开始
Time... is a river.
时间... 是一条河流
You have already made the decision.
你已经做出了决定
You make it every time.
你每次都会做决定
He's done the coin thing, has he?
他又拿硬币给你演示了 是吧?
You're the map maker.
你就是绘图者
I thought you needed rescuing?
我还以为你需要解救呢?
- I will.  - In the future?
- 会的  - 在将来?
The sooner you move beyond words like present and future,
你越早脱离现在和将来这些词汇
the sooner you become the man we need you to be.
就越早成为我们想要你成为的人
Are all the sons of Mithras unable to speak plainly?
密特拉之子都不会好好说话吗?
I admit, on occasion, we can be inscrutable, but so can you.
我承认 有时候我们很难理解 不过你也可以
I wanted to meet the storied Da Vinci,
我要在光天化日之下
in the bright of day.
见到那个传说中的达芬奇
We're different men, once hell breaks loose.
一旦鬼门关开启 我们就是不同的人了
And when's that happen?
什么时候会开启?
Hell happens when,
我们自认为道高一尺
the evil of this world exceeds our belief,
而当魔高一丈的时候
that we can conquer it.
灾难就要降临了
You ask me when you'll reach that point.
你问我你什么时候才能达到那个程度
I cannot say.
我不能说
Depends on you.
取决于你自己
Whatever befalls us, do not shirk from the task.
不管什么情况降临在我们头上 都不要退缩
I have a knack of rising to the occasion,
我有创造机会的能力
if I might only be told what the occasion is...
只要能告诉我是什么样的机会就行...
I venture to say it's true,
我冒险告诉你
what the sons of mithras have seen you in you,
密特拉之子们在你身上看到的都是真的
and you are closer every day, artista.
而且你每天都在接近 艺术家
- Closer to what?  - Wake up.
- 接近什么?  - 醒来
Where are you leading me?
你们要带我去哪?
L... leading you? Maestro, you're the one leading us.
带... 带你? 大师 是你在带路
What?
什么?
You woke us in the night, gave us one of your shopping lists.
你半夜叫醒我们 让我们去按照你的吩咐准备东西
Buy more magnesium,
买更多的镁粉
obtain obscure alcoholic beverages from the east,
买些东方产不知名的酒精饮料
acquire three horses...
三匹马...
You had some plan. Do you not remember?
你有计划的 忘了吗?
I do, I do. I remember it.
我有 有 我想起来了
- How long have we...  - Days.
- 我们已经...  - 几天了
You've been a sullen fuck the entire trip,
这一路上你都生着气
all for some foreign halfwit who got himself abducted.
就为某个被劫持的外国傻货
- The abyssinian.  - It's like...
- 阿比西亚人  - 好像...
It's like I'm just waking up.
我好想刚睡醒一样
I lost part of myself on the journey.
我在路上丢失了部分自我
- Journey where?  - It's not where...
- 去哪里的路上?  - 不是哪里...
it's when.
是何时
The evils of this world.
这个世界的恶魔
There's something odd around the castle.
城堡周围有些奇怪的东西
- What's this?  - You'll see what it does.
- 这是什么?  - 看看就明白了
Whose kingdom is this?
这是谁的领土?
The locals call him Stepes.
当地人叫他斯戴普斯
That's the man we've come to confront?
我们来找的就是他?
The one who has your captive is the fucking impaler?
抓了你要的战俘的是个该死的暴君?
I lost my right eye in battle.
我在战斗中瞎了右眼
Removed the bridge of my nose, so I'd still have peripheral vision.
摘掉鼻梁之后 这样我还能有一些间接视力
There.
就这样
Clever, eh?
很聪明 对吧?
That is quite... gleaming.
很是... 亮眼
And so we should explain our reason for being here.
我们来解释一下来这里的原因吧
- Piero?  - May I?
- 皮耶罗?  - 可以吗?
The two papal states flank your land and mine,
在你我领地之间有两块教皇的土地
and while we can watch Rome with one eye...
在我们一只眼睛盯着罗马的时候...
we must always keep another...eye,
总要用另一只... 呃眼睛
always on the pope's property, to the north.
盯着北方教皇的土地
Unless...
除非...
the northern realm became our property.
北方领土成为我们的
And how would that happen?
要怎么实现呢?
Well, if we allied ourselves.
哦 如果我们结盟
Florence and Urbino.
佛罗伦萨和乌尔比诺
It'd make sense if we could carve up the northern papal territory between us.
我们分割领土之间的教皇土地就成为可能了
I can annexe the city of bologna and its environs.
我可以征服博洛尼亚城和它附属的土地
You could double your port capacity on the adriatic.
而你可以让自己在亚得里亚海的港口翻倍
A bold stroke, but why don't I conquer it myself?
果断一击 不过为什么我不能自己征服这一整片呢?
I have the army. What do you offer up?
我出人 你出什么?
Money, of course,
当然是出钱
from the largest banking concern in all of Europe.
从全欧洲最大的银行
From each of us, as he is...
从我们每个受到...
blessed.
眷顾的人手里
Scared you, didn't I?
吓到你了 是吧?
That'll be fine, Medici.
别紧张 美第奇
I shouldn't provoke my own godson,
我不该刺激我的教子的
but I like to test a man.
不过我喜欢考验人
You've grown to be a worthy ally.
你证明了自己是个值得信任的盟友
And it's been too long since I led my men into combat.
而且我已经很久没有带人参加过战斗了
Our proposal is timely, indeed.
看来 我们的请求非常适时
I knew you had something juicy in mind,
你来找我的时候
when you showed up on my doorstep.
我就看出你心里有鬼了
There's no way you'd caravan all this distance
你大老远跑来
just to watch me take a shit.
肯定不是来看我拉屎的
Their turbans are nailed to their skulls.
头巾被钉在头骨上
All Turkish. Clearly this warlord has an issue with the Ottomans.
这都是土耳其人的尸体 显然城堡主人和土耳其打过仗
His bravery against the Turks won him 13 years in prison.
他勇猛抗击土耳其 最后坐了十三年牢
But, seeing as none of us are Turks ourselves,
既然我们都不是土耳其人
we should have nothing to fear.
就没有什么好担心的了
You don't think, with my blood, someone could take me for a Turk?
他不会误把我当做土耳其人吧?
How do I know this warlord's eyes aren't failing?
我怎么知道他不会看错人?
Because I spotted you from miles away.
因为我从很远就听见你了
Though I were blind, I could hear the clattering
虽然我失明 但我能听到你们谈话
and nattering of your tartar tongue from further yet.
从很远就能听见你们鞑靼人在这瞎扯
- I'm not a Tartar.  - What are you, then?
- 我不是鞑靼人  - 那你是谁?
- Unique.  - Unique?
- 一个不同寻常的人  - 不同寻常?
Dung beetles think they're unique.
屎壳郎也觉得自己不同寻常啊
Your mongrel half-breed lineage speaks louder than your words.
一听你就是混血的杂种
You see god, well, has many punishments for mankind.
上帝用各种手段惩罚人类
Earthquakes, volcanoes, plagues and cancers.
地震 火山喷发 瘟疫 癌症
Worse than these, he sent the Turks and the Tartars
更糟的是 他送来了土耳其和鞑靼人
and the mongrels, like you.
还有你这样的杂种
Ave, vladislaus Dracula filius,
贵安 弗拉德龙骑士之子
Vaivoda partium transalpinarum.
特兰西瓦尼亚公国王子
Prince of Transylvania and Wallachia,
特兰西瓦尼亚和瓦拉几亚公国王子
Son of Vlad II known as Vlad Dracul, or Vlad the Dragon,
弗拉德二世 名为弗拉・德拉库或弗拉德龙骑士
which makes you Vlad III, Son of the Dragon.
您是弗拉德三世 龙骑士之子
Or as it is known in your language, Dracula.
在您的语言里称为 德拉库拉
Impressive, your command of my titles,
很好 你知道我的爵号
but tell me who you are and what you want here.
现在告诉我 你是谁 到这来干什么
My name is Maestro Leonardo.
我是莱昂纳多大师
These are my companions, Nico, Zoroaster.
这是我的同伴 尼科和琐罗亚斯德
We were sent by the magnificent Lorenzo De Medici
我们是佛罗伦萨总督
of the Republic of Florence.
洛伦佐・美第奇派来的
All of Italy wonders at your victories against the Ottomans,
全意大利都想知道您是怎样打败土耳其人的
and my lord extends his friendship
我的领主希望和您交好
and seeks military counsel for the greater glory
并请您到佛罗伦萨和瓦拉吉亚公国
of Florence and Wallachia.
做军事顾问
You must know this land has been bedeviled by war,
你知道这片土地已经被战争
and worse than war.
折磨得满目疮痍
We shall talk more...
我们可以...
at dinner.
边吃边谈
As long as the dinner's not us.
但愿他要吃的不是我们
So we're selling tickets to the papal baths now, are we?
教皇的浴室现在只要购票就可以进来了 是吗?
An urgent matter has arisen.
这是件紧急的事
Urgent enough that you sully this chamber with her presence?
紧急到你都可以让她进来玷污这里吗?
I know where to find whores if I want them.
我知道在哪能找到妓女 不用你找
We thought it best you hear this news directly from her lips.
我们觉得你最好直接听她汇报
I've come from Florence, your holiness.
我刚从佛罗伦萨来 陛下
And does your absence from the city...
你从城里跑出来...
create no suspicion?
不会引起怀疑吗?
My aunt in Siena is providing me with an alibi.
我在锡耶纳的姑妈会给我找借口脱身
No-one of import will miss me in Florence.
佛罗伦萨没有政要会惦记我
Certainly your husband doesn't fall into the category of import.
显然你丈夫不属于那种人
What of Lorenzo's war engineer,
洛伦佐的战争工程师最近怎么样?
in whom the count seems so fascinated?
洛伦佐特别赞赏的那个
Da Vinci has set out from the city.
达芬奇离开了城市
No man knows where.
没人知道他去了哪里
Nor woman?
女的也不知道?
Nor I.
我也不知道
Lorenzo himself has left Florence.
洛伦佐本人也离开了佛罗伦萨
As we speak,
现在
he makes an embassy to the duke of Urbino,
他正在会见乌尔比诺公爵
fresh with the credit of his dealings
也刚与斐迪南和伊莎贝拉
with Ferdinand and Isabella.
达成协议
He seeks to create a new military alliance.
他希望与他们建立新的军事联盟
The calculating rogue.
这个深谋远虑的流氓
Far from reeling at our attempts to weaken his rule,
我们试图削弱洛伦佐的势力
Lorenzo courts the most accomplished mercenaries
可是他却在半岛上召集起了一支
on the peninsula.
训练有素的军队
I know what the naval do with them.
我知道他们的行动是什么
He and Urbino will march north.
他和乌尔比诺将会向北进军
Together, they'll sack our lands surrounding Bologna
一起掠夺我们博洛尼亚的土地
and divide them up.
然后将其瓜分
How do you know, holy father?
您是怎么知道的 神父?
Because it's exactly what I'd do, you fucking coward.
因为我也会这样做 你这该死的懦夫
Look at the lot of you.
看看你们
Too scared to bring me this news yourselves.
吓得不敢把这消息告诉我
Hiding behind this Florentine slit.
躲在这个佛罗伦萨淫妇身后
How can I wonder Lorenzo resists me so well,
看看我这些手下的怂样
when I see the quality of my allies?
难怪洛伦佐能轻而易举地抵抗我
We only tried to serve your glory.
我们只想尽力为您效忠
We had not the benefit of your divine guidance.
我们没想享受您的神圣指引
Guidance? You want guidance?
指引? 你想要指引?
Do you remember what proved I was chosen by god?
还记得上帝选择我的征兆吗?
So... So many things, your holiness.
有很... 很多征兆 陛下
The way I survived drowning as a child.
我小时候没有被水淹死
Let's see how you do.
让我看看你怎么样
Holy father, surely... a loving god shows mercy.
神父 无疑... 仁慈的上帝会宽恕他的
You dare question me?
你敢质疑我?
The rock upon which god's words stands.
你敢质疑上帝所说的话
Kiss this ring.
吻这枚戒指
My bath is ruined.
你们毁了我的沐浴
I don't care how, end the House of Medici,
不管你用什么手段 给我干掉美第奇家族
before I end you.
不然我就干掉你
Dinner awaits.
晚宴已备好
How are we supposed to free the captive from a place like this?
我们怎么才能把那人救出来?
If I knew that, I'd be Da Vinci.
要是我知道 我就叫达芬奇了
You've dropped some change.
你把钱扔在地上了
Of course, you'll have noticed the money.
你当然会看到这些钱
The sultanis is a base currency...
苏丹币是东方异教徒使用的...
for the heathen ruler of the East.
低劣货币
You see, this is how I allow my soldiers
这样我的士兵们就能向我
to prove their loyalty to me.
证明他们的忠诚
I toss these sultanis on the ground before them.
我把这些苏丹币扔到地上 扔到他们面前
And, do you know, the coins are never, ever touched?
你知道吗? 这些硬币从未被碰过
It's just they've fallen quite randomly,
胡乱扔这些货币的话
you'd really notice if one was gone?
你能听出哪个被捡走了?
I miss nothing.
我从不遗漏
Please, now.
请坐吧
A little Tuscan wine,
喝点托斯卡纳酒
just to make you feel at home, no?
找找家的感觉 怎么样?
Thank you.
谢谢
I must say, I'm impressed with your hospitality,
您刚从狱中逃出来 却这样热情好客
so soon after your escape from captivity.
很让我感动
I am, sadly, at home in dungeons.
因为我习惯了狱中的生活
As a child, my father sent my brother and me
小时候 父亲把我的兄弟和我
to be hostages held by the Turkish sultan.
送给土耳其苏丹做人质
The prisons converted my damnable brother
我的兄弟最终在狱中叛变
to the cause of the Turks, but not me.
他投降了土耳其 而我没有
I learned to trust nobody.
我学会了不相信任何人
To survive any pain, the dogs, the dungeons,
不相信任何人才能在痛苦 恶狗 地牢
even a lightning strike,
甚至在给我留下
which has left me with this... web of scars.
这疤痕的闪电中幸存
Now I spend every waking hour in resistance to my brother...
如今我每时每刻都要反抗我的兄弟...
and the fucking Turks.
和该死的土耳其人
Well your victories against them have been recognized,
所有人都认可你的胜利
even by the pope.
甚至罗马教皇
If we're going to raise a toast,
如果要干杯
let's lift a glass to the one who helped me out of the prison this time,
请敬给那个助我逃离监狱的
to the Bringer of Light himself.
光明使者
Who, my lord?
是谁 殿下?
Lucifer, the Bringer of Light.
路西华 光明的使者
Most beautiful of all the angels.
众天使中最美的一个
And how did Lucifer help you?
撒旦怎样帮你?
Like me, Lucifer rose against a tyrant.
和我一样 路西华反抗暴君
Like me, he was abandoned and betrayed by the god he loved.
和我一样 被他所爱的上帝抛弃和背叛
I made a pact with Lucifer to win my freedom
我和路西华定下了协议 他将给我自由
and ascend to my throne one last time.
并协我最后一次登上王座
Do you know?
你知道吗?
I don't find it hard to live without a soul.
没有了灵魂 我并不感到痛苦
Lucifer.
敬路西华
And how fortuitous for Da Vinci.
怎么那么巧啊
The clever devil leaves just as I arrive with questions.
我刚要来询问问题 这个聪明鬼就出城了
You don't find that curious?
你不觉得好奇吗?
Trust me, signor, that's the least curious thing about him.
相信我 先生 这是他最不值得好奇的事
What is your relationship with him?
你和他什么关系?
We had our day...
我们好过...
but that's all it was, a day.
但也就那么一天而已
And, anyway, his eye is set on another.
他总是专注于其它的事
- How do you know?  - I'm a woman.
- 你怎么知道?  - 我是女人
No, of course we're friends.
我们当然只是朋友
He saved my life and, for that, I deeply admire him.
他救过我一命 所以我很钦佩他
That hasn't become illegal, has it?
这并不违法 对吧?
It has if it hurts Florence.
影响了佛罗伦萨的安全 那就是违法的
All I want is your help in guarding her.
我想让你帮忙保卫佛罗伦萨
I don't know where he's gone.
我不知道他去哪了
You keep his confidences well.
你很为他保守秘密
I'd like to lie to anyone else, excellency,
我可以和其他人撒谎 阁下
but not you.
但我不会对你撒谎
Although, if you tried to force it out of me,
但是 要是你逼我撒谎的话
I'd be helpless to stop you.
我也就没有办法了
Perhaps we should discuss this somewhere else.
或许我们应该到别处去谈
- Somewhere more quiet?  - Mm.
- 找个更安静的地方?  - 恩
Until we make it less so.
在那里欢闹一下
The city gates are closed.
城门已经关了
Two minutes to curfew, scoundrel.
离宵禁还有两分钟 混蛋
Either you get your arses home or spend the night here.
赶紧回家 不然就整夜待在这别走
Persons caught roaming the streets after curfew get put in my little book.
谁宵禁后还在街上闲逛 我就把他的名字
Being put in my little book means you explain your transgressions to the judge.
记到册子上 然后你就得向法官解释了
Signor Medici, forgive me.
美第奇先生 抱歉
I hadn't seen you with a bar wench.
我没看到你和她在一起
- Your little book?  - My ledger, full of pigs, mostly.
- 你的小册子?  - 我的记录本上面记满了蠢货
You record every curfew violation?
每桩违禁你都有记录?
Since the day it was declared.
自从禁令开始以来都有
If one were to study these, one might see who was out,
所以如果查的话 可以查出有谁在不该出门的时候
when they shouldn't have been?
私自跑出去吗?
Yes, if one were a glutton for punishment.
没错 然后那个人就要挨罚了
Take me to them.
给我看看那些册子
One could speak weeks paging through these records.
看这些记录可能要花几周的时间
Then we're in luck. According to my brother, I'm great at wasting time.
那太好了 我兄弟说我最擅长浪费时间
Your secret, sir?
说说你的秘诀 先生?
Oh, it's a matter of knowing which elements to blend.
噢 知道要混合什么元素就好了
Magnesium here, iron filings there, so on.
加点镁粉 再加点铁粉之类的
I think it's ingenious.
我觉得这很有创意
Does it have a military application?
这个能应用到军事上吗?
Not yet.
还不行
Well, then, we must talk further.
好吧 那我们以后一定还会再谈
Since I've renounced your christian gods,
自从我放弃基督上帝
I've only my wits and ferocity to protect me
我就只能用智慧和残暴
from the forces of Sultan Mehmed II.
来抗击苏丹穆罕默德二世的军队了
Perhaps the ingenuity you bring to Lorenzo's court
或许你给洛伦佐的这个发明
could benefit me as well.
也可以让我受益
Now...
现在...
since you've shown me your little party piece,
既然你为我展示了这宴会节目
I will respond in kind with a little diversion of my own.
我也要展示一下我的小消遣
You see, without a soul weighing me down,
你看啊 失去了沉重的灵魂
I can see in the dark.
我的视线可以穿透黑暗
I cannot be killed.
我无法被杀死
I can enjoy certain entertainments
我可以享受一些几年前
that may have made me blanch years ago.
可能会吓得我面色惨白的娱乐节目
This is the last of the retinue of a Turkish ambassador
这是土耳其使臣的最后一个随从
who was foolish enough to approach me.
他愚蠢地试图接近我
I miss no opportunity in reminding the Turks
我要让土耳其人记住
of the childhood they provided.
他们给我的童年
Is it the one we're looking for?
这是我们要找的那个人吗?
Unshackle him.
给他松镣
Now... prove stronger than your friends.
现在... 请你证明你比自己那些朋友强
Defeat these dogs and you will go free.
打败这两只狗 我就放你自由
And please don't think me so inhuman
别觉得我灭绝人性
that I wouldn't give you a fighting chance.
连搏斗的机会都不给你
Here's a butter knife.
给你这把黄油刀
Please! Don't!
求求你! 不要!
This...
这...
This is justice.
这才是正义
So... shall we send for the main course?
我们可以上主菜了吗?
I can't eat.
我吃不下去
My tastes are not universally shared, it's true.
我的口味不是人人都喜欢
- Let us retire.  - Before we do...
- 我们散席吧  - 在那之前...
you have honored us with the traditional wine of our homeland,
您为我们准备了我们家乡的传统酒
and so do we honor you, with the traditional liquor of Wallachia.
我们也为您准备了传统的瓦拉吉亚酒
- You've brought tuica?  - Mm-hm.
- 你买了图伊卡酒?  - 嗯
Well, our master in Florence would spare no expense
我们佛罗伦萨的总督对您表示钦佩
to demonstrate his admiration for you, my lord.
所以绝不会对您吝啬 殿下
To Vlad III.
敬弗拉德三世
When have I ever known you to hesitate about a drink, my friend?
我从没见过你们喝酒也会犹豫啊 朋友?
Good.
好
And some for your maid? Your men?
给你的仆人也尝一尝吧? 你的随从?
- Yes.  - Yes? Good.
- 好  - 好? 恩
There you go.
好的
Some for you... Some for you.
你来一点... 你也来一点
Show the friends to a room.
为这些朋友找个房间
- Some for you.  - Once my guards have toasted our guests,
- 来尝一点  - 等我的随从给客人敬酒之后
The artisan and I will parley further.
我还有话要和艺术家谈谈
How about your dogs, who entertained us so well, this evening?
给你的狗也尝尝怎么样? 今天娱乐节目很卖力
There's some for you, for you, the last little drop.
给你一些 最后一点给你
Please don't be unsettled by the vermin.
请别觉得难受
I welcome them.
我欢迎老鼠
Often, in prison, they were my only friends.
通常在监狱里 他们是我唯一的朋友
Well, I know what it is to be thrown into a cell.
我知道被关在地窖里什么感受
Without the companionship of the bats,
没有蝙蝠陪伴
I would not have survived.
我不可能活下来
You see.
你看
- We understand each other.  - Hmm.
- 我们能相互理解  - 恩
Come.
来吧
Beautiful, is it not?
很漂亮 对吧?
You see, this is why I wanted to return to castle Poenari so badly.
所以我才那么渴望回到波奈里古堡来
From the heights...
站在这高度...
I can almost forget the decades the Turks
我几乎可以忘却几十年来
have been living underneath the earth.
那些被关在地牢里的土耳其人
It's a shame, then, that was the last of them.
很遗憾 刚才那是最后一个土耳其人了
Oh, there is one more.
噢 其实还有一个
Their master, Solomon Ogbai.
他们的主人所罗门・奥拜
The name Ogbai,
奥拜这个名字
In Amharic, it means don't take him away.
在阿姆哈拉语中 是"别带他走"的意思
Yeah.
是啊
Indeed.
没错
For stooping to serve them,
为了报复他们让我卑躬屈膝
I take my time with the Abyssinian.
我在这个埃塞俄比亚人身上花了很长时间
I keep him ready for my personal whims.
为了我的兴趣爱好 我把他关了起来
I invent new ways to torture, just for him.
我为他发明了新的折磨方式
There is a window, near where I keep him.
我把他关在靠窗户的地方
He cannot see the view.
他看不到窗外
So I said I would recreate the scenery for him...
我说要是他能找来...
if he would only provide me with
制作小模型的材料
the raw material for a suitable miniature.
我可以为他造出那个景色来
These are the crenulations of the towers outside my window...
这是我窗外那些塔的模型...
carved in the abyssinian's own flesh.
是用那埃塞俄比亚人的肉刻出来的
There is one frontier he shall never stop exploring.
他将永远看不到痛苦的边界
Agony.
痛苦
May I share a confession with you?
我能和你说句真心话吗?
Yeah, yes...
当然...
if it pleases, my lord.
请吧 殿下
I know...
我知道...
that I'm mad.
我疯了
Indeed.
确实
But will you tell me how I could be otherwise?
但请告诉我 不然我还能怎样?
A father rips a child from his home,
父亲把孩子从家里带走
from everything he knows
夺去孩子熟识的一切
and tosses him into the claws of his worst enemy.
然后把他扔到自己敌人的手掌中
Well, we are...
我们...
We are too often what our fathers make us.
我们的命运通常被父亲决定了
Whether we like it or not, better or for worse.
不管我们是否愿意 是好是坏
Oh, yes.
是的
In my case, definitely for worse.
我的情况肯定糟糕的
You see, my father, he taught me
我父亲教给我
that cruelty is the only true currency of the universe,
残酷是全世界的通行货币
and now I am the richest man in all of christendom.
如今我是基督国家最富有的人了
Ha!
哈!
- My god, it is true.  - Yes?
- 天啊 你真在这里  - 恩?
Servants told me you were carrying books upon books into your quarters.
仆人告诉我 你抱了一大堆书回来
I wondered if they'd been raiding the wine cellar.
我还以为他们喝多了
- I'm easy to tease.  - Only sometimes.
- 我很好取笑吗  - 只是有时而已
Well, at least you have a hobby you love.
好吧 至少你有自己的爱好
And what is your new hobby?
那你这个新爱好是什么?
The Florentine obsession with record keeping is paying off.
佛罗伦萨人爱收藏记录的癖好有回报了
These are the records to every guard at every station in the city.
这些是城里每个守卫 在每个站点的巡逻记录
Anyone who breaks curfew even for a slight reason will be put down here.
无论什么理由 违反宵禁的人都会被记录下来
Including, I suppose, the true spy,
包括那个真正的间谍
whom you believe framed Becchi.
那个诬陷贝奇的人
You smirk, but there are mysteries to be solved here.
没错 可现在还有些问题
For example, why do these symbols from the zodiac keep coming up?
比如 为什么里面有这么多星座的符号?
This. That's the sign for capricorn, I think.
这个 我觉得是摩羯座的符号
And this, that's aquarius, yes?
这个是水瓶座 对吧?
With certain sensitive subjects of Florence,
因为佛罗伦萨的某些贵族比较在意
their names are indicated with symbols,
自己的名字被列进违反宵禁的名单
rather than list them clearly as violators of the curfew.
所以就用符号代替他们的名字了
Ah. This date I recall.
啊 这个日期我记得
After a long night of carousing, I was questioned on my way home,
那天参加完整夜酒宴之后 我回家的路上被盘问了
So is this the symbol for me?
所以这个符号代表我吗?
Athletic champion that you are,
因为您是体育冠军
Sagittarius is a natural code name for you.
射手座的符号再适合您不过
Tell us the identity behind each of these symbols, then.
那快告诉我这些符号都代表谁
I'm not privy to that knowledge.
我也不知道这些符号的意思
- That's in captain Dragonetti's office.  - Obtain it for me.
- 这些都在德拉戈奈蒂队长的办公室里  - 给我拿来
Becchi would be proud of you.
贝奇会为你感到骄傲的
The man we're here to save must be dead by now.
我们要救的人肯定已经死了
No. No, not yet.
不 还没死
But... but we must move to save him now.
但是... 但是我们必须赶快救他
You two can go on.
你们两个去吧
- I feel like I could sleep for the next week.  - As could I.
- 我觉得我可以睡上一周  - 我也是
That's because we've all been poisoned.
那是因为我们中毒了
What?
什么?
Drink some antidote.
喝点解药
That bastard.
那个混蛋
- He slipped something in our drinks.  - No.
- 他在我们的酒里下毒  - 不是他
I did.
是我
There's nothing you won't do to us in your bloody quest.
为了你那血腥的追求 你什么事都能做出来
I... I adulterated the Tuica before we arrived.
我... 我在来之前给图伊卡酒里下了毒
That we'd all have to drink it, in order to convince him it was safe.
想让他相信酒是安全的 咱们必须先喝
And now...
现在...
everyone, including the dogs, should be passing out.
所有人 包括两条狗 都应该昏睡过去了
Ready?
准备好了吗?
How do you know where we're going?
你怎么会认识路?
It's a simple architectural assessment.
我做了简单的建筑结构分析
The Abyssinian pointed it out to me himself in a way.
那个埃塞俄比亚人用某种方式告诉了我
Do we wanna know what you mean?
你想告诉我们是什么方式吗?
No, actually, you don't.
其实你们最好别问
It's here.
就是这
Are you sure about this, maestro?
你确定吗 大师?
No.
不
What does that say?
写的什么?
Don't take me away.
不要带我走
Now, this, this is justice.
现在 这才是正义
To Vlad III.
敬弗拉德三世
Farewell greetings from a half-breed Mongrel.
我这个混血的杂种向您道别
Nico...
尼科...
go get the horses. I'll meet you outside.
去备马 我去外面找你们
Ah. That one.
啊 那一根
Careful. Careful. Careful.
小心 小心 小心
It's that one, then that one.
这一根 然后那一根
Not too fast, he'll be cut even deeper.
别太快 不然会割得更深
It's all over. It's OK. It's over.
没事了 可以了 都没事了
It's not. It's not.
没有 还没有
It's not him.
那个不是他
It's not Vlad.
不是弗拉德
Shit.
该死
Fuck me.
坏了
You're an arrogant little fool, aren't you?
你就是个自大的傻瓜 是吧?
I've endured every drug and poison known to man.
我免疫所有对人类有害的毒品和药剂
I fought off the Ottoman Empire.
我是从土耳其王国挣脱回来的
Do you really think that I would die at the hands,
你真的以为我会死在一个该死佛罗伦萨人
of a fucking Florentine?
手里吗?
Shit.
该死
Or a mongrel?
或者一个杂种手里吗?
How's that for a military application?
这东西当军事用品怎么样?
Zo, wake up!
琐罗 醒醒!
Wake up! Zo!
醒醒! 琐罗!
Life...
生命...
Life is a trap, don't you think?
生命就是个陷阱 你觉得呢?
Well, now, I'm going to set you free.
现在 我来放你自由
Curious.
有意思
You cannot kill a man without a soul.
没有灵魂的人你是杀不掉的
You must go.
你必须走
Do not shirk from the task.
不要退缩
Stay out of Florence for the next few days.
接下来的几天不要进佛罗伦萨城
Oh, and don't speak with Lorenzo, or anyone in the city.
哦 而且不要跟洛伦佐说话 跟城里谁也别讲话
I suppose I could go to Siena...
我觉得我可以去锡耶纳...
and create a story to explain my extended absence, but why?
编个故事解释我为什么不在 不过为什么呢?
You've seen what happens,
怀疑教廷计划
when people question the plans of the Vatican, haven't you?
是什么下场 你见过了吧?
I have.
见过了
Speak to nobody along the road.
路上不要跟任何人讲话
And make sure no-one speaks with you.
也确定没人跟你讲话
That shouldn't be a problem.
这应该不难
I have a strategy.
我有办法
- Have some men follow her.  - Of course.
- 派人跟着她  - 明白
Then discreetly have her killed.
然后悄悄地杀了她
Her value to us has been exhausted.
她对我们已经没有利用价值了
She's...
她...
compromised by her affections for Da Vinci.
已经被自己对达芬奇的感情所影响了
Did his holiness order this?
是教皇命令这么做的吗?
Do it outside the walls of Florence.
在接近佛罗伦萨的地方动手
Leave no ties to Rome.
不要留下跟罗马有关的线索
Make it look like bandits did it.
布置成土匪杀人越货的样子
Oh, and er... have them drive stakes through her eyes.
哦 还要... 刺穿她的双眼
She's seen too much.
她看到的太多了
The guards, the dogs, they're gonna rouse soon.
守卫 还有狗 就快醒过来了
Where did you get that wound?
这伤口是哪来的?
There are more urgent things to explain.
还有比这重要的事情要解释
- Did you know this would happen?  - I knew it might.
- 你知道会这样吗?  - 我知道有可能
I had to take that chance, for the book of leaves.
我不得不抓住机会 为了叶之书
Sword.
剑给我
Maestro, shall we see to his injuries?
大师 我们给他处理一下伤口吗?
They're beyond seeing to and I cannot meet my end here.
还有更要紧的事 而且我也不能死在这
In other words, fuck this place.
换句话说 离开这个鬼地方吧
I want to spit on Vlad's body.
我要往弗拉德的尸体上吐口唾沫
Yeah. Well, you could if we knew where it was.
是 可以 如果能找到在哪就行
Where the fuck is he?
他妈的跑哪去了?
Just come on! Let's go!
别管了! 走吧!
Maybe some creature dragged him off.
也许是有什么动物给拖走吃了
Let's not find out. Come on.
咱们别管了 走吧
You really must try this, Camilla.
你一定要试试这个 卡米拉
Surely you have a sweeter tooth than your brother.
你肯定比你哥哥喜欢甜食
You certainly have a sweeter smile.
你的笑都比他甜
Some honey.
加点蜂蜜
The pride of the Duchy of Urbino.
乌尔比诺公爵领地的特产
Oh, I've made arrangements with their duke.
我跟他们的公爵协约了
With rawn like his, I pity those who wish harm upon Florence.
有了他的强援 我真可怜那些妄图侵害佛罗伦萨的人
You'll have your hands full with that one.
这样你会赚到盆满钵满的
Federico Da Montefeltro's a... colorful character indeed.
费德里科・达・蒙泰费尔特罗是个... 很有意思的人
- Did you invite us here to show off your new alliance?  - Bernardo!
- 你邀请我们来是要炫耀新的盟友的吗?  - 伯纳德!
I don't recall inviting you at all, Signor Baroncelli.
巴龙切利先生 我都不记得邀请过你
Perhaps you fail to understand why I went to Urbino.
也许你是没理解我去乌尔比诺的原因
You think Rome will look after the Pazzis.
你觉得罗马会照顾帕吉家族
But, when all is said and done,
不过 等一切都过去之后
Rome only looks after Rome.
罗马照顾的只有罗马自己
And you both of you are loyal sons of Florence.
而你们二位都是佛罗伦萨的皇家子弟
Don't you think the time has come for union in our republic...
你们难道不认为我们自己共和制下结合的时代已经到来了...
not further divisions?
而不是吃里扒外?
My brother Giuliano has a stubborn mind,
我弟弟朱利亚诺脑子很笨
but a good heart.
不过心肠很好
At one point, we hoped to see him in a cardinal's hat,
某个角度上讲 我们也想让他受到教皇的封赐
but our current relations with the church have precluded that.
不过以我们目前与教廷的关系行不通了
And yet, a young man like Giuliano, needs a future.
不过 一个朱利亚诺这样的年轻人 需要未来
He would make a fine husband for Camilla...
他应该可以成为卡米拉的好丈夫...
would he not?
不是吗?
Honey, anyone?
还有人要加蜂蜜吗?
Farewell.
再会
Arrivederci.
再会(意大利语)
Whether or not the Pazzis agree to this union, I have to ask,
不管帕吉家族同不同意这次联姻 我都要问
did you consult your brother about this?
你问过你弟弟这件事情了吗?
Giuliano's interests are the interests of Florence.
朱利亚诺的利益就是佛罗伦萨的利益
Don't worry. I'll have breakable objects removed from the room before I broach the topic.
别担心 我跟他谈之前 会拿走房间里所有易碎品
She is the child of our enemy, Signor.
她可是我们敌人的孩子 阁下
Some might argue he is being thrown to the wolves.
会有人认为我们把他送入虎口的
You underestimate my brother, Piero.
你低估我弟弟了 皮耶罗
We are not feeding these wolves.
我们不是割肉饲虎
We are taming them.
而是驯虎
Did you know he was going to propose this?
你知道他要提这个事情吗?
I had an inkling...
算是有吧...
seeing as it was my idea.
正合我意
- You've had your elixir?  - Relax.
- 你服药了吗?  - 别紧张
They say children conceived in frustration are born bitter.
据说在挫折时怀上的孩子出生都会痛苦
You'll understand I'm agitated by this league of devils around us.
你会明白我们周围这些恶魔们已经让我焦虑不安了
After our ploy with the Pazzis,
经过我们对帕吉家族的计划之后
you're not ready for another master stroke.
你还没有准备好再一次行动
Our doctor said this position is more likely to conceive us a male heir.
医生说这个方子更容易让我们怀上个男孩
Men would prefer a position where a woman's face,
男人都喜欢把女人的脸压得很低
is rammed down so far she can't even speak.
低到甚至不能说话的姿势
I'm sorry, what was that, dear?
抱歉 你说什么 亲爱的?
Please.
来吧
Wooo!
喔!
It was the cage.
是铁笼
It was the cage. It was the cage.
是铁笼 铁笼割的
The words written on the don't take him away.
上面写的字说不要带他走
It wasn't a taunt, it was a warning.
不是讽刺 是警告
Vlad built the device to eviscerate you if you were freed...
如果你被救出来 弗拉德制造的这个装置...
to rip an unstanchable wound.
就会撕开一条暗伤
I should've realized.
我早该发现的
- I'm sorry.  - Never mind.
- 抱歉  - 没关系
I must tell you of the key you seek.
我必须给你讲讲你要找的钥匙
The other key that opens the vault of heaven?
打开天穹的另一把钥匙?
Yes, tell me.
对 告诉我
It's waiting in Rome, there for your taking.
在罗马 等你去拿
And, when you have both keys...
而且 当你拿到两把钥匙的时候...
your mother, Caterina.
你母亲卡特琳娜
She is alive.
她还活着
She carries the book of leaves for us,
她为我们带着叶之书
beneath the post of the sun in a town made of stone...
在我地图里那块大陆上...
in a land on my map.
石头小镇的太阳之柱下
Why... I need you to decode the map.
为什么... 我需要你给我解释地图
Then you may take what you need.
那你就要拿走你需要的
Here.
在这
Here is the secret to deciphering the map.
这就是能破译地图的秘密
I will not survive to come with you.
我不可能活着跟你走
You must cut my flesh loose and take it with you...
等我死了你必须把它割下来...
once I die.
带走
The turk said that I would save you.
那个土耳其人说我可以解救你
And so you will...
而且你会的...
someday...
某一天...
but not today.
不过不是今天
But there are so many things you must learn first.
但之前你还有很多事情要学
Yes? Yes?
是吗? 什么?
You must learn that anything is possible...
你要学会一切皆有可能...
including defeat.
包括失败
- You must... learn...  - What? What?
- 你要... 学会...  - 什么? 什么?
What?
什么?
- What? What?  - Maestro...
- 什么? 什么?  - 大师...
- I must must learn what?  - Maestro, he's gone.
- 我要学会什么?  - 大师 他死了
- Maestro.  - I must learn what?
- 大师  - 我要学会什么?
I must learn...
我要学会...
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
该死! 该死! 该死!
Fuck! Fuck.
该死! 该死
I've been here before.
我来过这
- No, this isn't the path we came in on.  - No. No.
- 没有 这不是我们来的路  - 不 不是那个意思
This is where the Abyssinian and I first met.
这是我跟阿比西亚人第一次见面的地方
He warned me...
他警告我...
I thought I could solve things...
我觉得可以解决问题...
like I always do.
如往常一样
Hell happens...
我们自认为道高一尺...
when the evil of the world exceeds our belief,
而当魔高一丈的时候
that we can conquer it.
灾难就要降临了